Rudra Dave

Front-end Developer

Connect

- +91 9328946515
- in rudra-dave-8144302b8
- C Rudradave0901
- Ahmedabad India
- Portfolio.com

Languages

English

Hindi

Gujarati

Skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

Frameworks

Bootstrap, Tailwind, Jquery, ReactJS

Tools

Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio, Sublime 3.

Other

Linux, mongoDB, Git, Github.

Soft Skills

Communication

Team collaboration

Time management

About Me

As a Front-end Developer with 2.5+ year of hands-on experience in crafting responsive and engaging web applications and websites. I am excited to join an organization where I can showcase and further develop my skills, contribute to driving business growth, and seize opportunities for career advancement while contributing to the organization's success.

Education

Deepak Highschool Amreli - 365601

2017-2018

10th (SSC) - 63.8%

Deepak Highschool Amreli - 365601

2019-2020

12th (HSC) - 57.3%

PKM College, BKNMU University - Junagadh

2020-2023

Bachelor's Of Computer Application (BCA) Graduated With CGPA: 8.3/10

Work Experience

Fronted Developer @ TXlabs (Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India | June 2024 - Present)

- Collaborated with backend teams to ensure secure API integration.
- Applied secure coding practices to build web applications and protect against XSS and CSRF attacks.
- ☑ Implemented access control mechanisms to safeguard sensitive user data.

Fronted Developer @ Glorywebs- Creatives PVT. LTD (Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India | April 2023 - May 2024)

- © Developed responsive and user-friendly websites and web applications using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- © Collaborated with backend teams to develop secure authentication mechanisms using OAuth 2.0 and JWT.
- © Developed modules that emphasized web application security basics. and Developed and monitored error logs to detect anomalies that could indicate potential security issues.
- Trained students on secure coding standards and best practices to prevent web vulnerabilities.

Web development Trainer @ IANT - institute of Advance Network Technology (Junagadh, Gujarat, India | Oct 2022 - March 2023)

- © Conducted comprehensive training sessions on web development technologies, including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and popular frameworks like React etc
- Designed and delivered engaging curriculum and course materials tailored to diverse learner backgrounds and skill levels.

Achievements

- ⊗ Reduced security issues by 30% through proactive log monitoring.
- ⊘ Improved site responsiveness across devices by implementing TailwindCSS.
- © Built and deployed 10+ responsive websites and web apps using React, Next.js, and TailwindCSS.
- ② Improved load speed of a major client website by 45% using front-end performance optimizations.
- ⊘ Integrated PDF and Excel reading libraries to enhance data management features in real-time dashboards.